Soumyajit Ghosh Data Engineer



(91) 8961883837



soumyaghosh257@gmail.com.in

Soumvajit Ghosh



Kolkata, West Bengali

OBJECTIVE

A result driven passionate leader with an exceptional technical background. More than 6.5 years of technical leadership experience in Azure Data Engineering, Customer handling and Technology Operations. Known for bringing high energy, creative out of the box solution, extensive understanding of root causes for issues and appropriate solutions to problems and delivering complex program.

Technologies

- ServiceNow, JIRA, Confluence
- Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL, Azure Synapse Analytics, Azure Databricks, Azure Data lake
- PostgreSQL, Oracle SQL, MS SQL
- Unix, Python, PySpark
- **RPA AA and UI Path**
- BY CKB, Spaceplanning, Floorplanning, BY Open Access
- **Dynatrace**

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Allianz Technology SE (APRIL 2023 - PRESENT)

Data Engineer, April 2023-Present

- Working in a Global Reporting project to provide an end-to-end business solution to help customers to make data-driven decisions.
- Maintaining, scaling, and supporting 10+ existing data pipelines and 20+ analytical pipelines.
- Designed and developed scalable data pipeline in Azure Data Factory to process large datasets.
- Maintaining data pipelines uptime of 99% while ingesting and loading data for 10 different OEs.
- Loading monthly data for 10 different OEs in 3 different environments as UAT, Integration and Prod by pulling the data with ADF pipelines on a request basis to visualize the latest refreshed data on the dashboard.
- Monitoring automated daily, weekly, monthly azure pipelines and flagging any failures with initial investigation and collaboration with Data Quality team to provide resolution.
- Led the development for automated ETL processes to reduce manual task by 20% and improve the overall data quality.
- Led cross-functional initiative to enhance data lineage, boosting traceability and supporting compliance requirements.
- Providing incident and request support and closing them after final resolution.

$U\underline{ST\ Global\ (\texttt{December 2021-April 2023})}$

Cloud migration co-ordinator, October 2021-April 2023

- Responsible for planning and coordinating activities outside of BAU of CMM or TAM scope.
- Responsible for driving core Migrations account team as well as coordinating with Product, Platform and Migrations leadership to prevent blockers and escalations by removing risks, clear blockers and share

- updates and learning across the highest levels of the organization with the goal to improve repeatability/standardization.
- Responsible for communicating updates/asks and escalations to Hierarchy, Customer Support, Customer Success leadership and coordinate with Mission Control Program Manager to documentation and updates.
- Coordinated with key roles like Business Lead, Escalation Manager, Content Manager, CSM, TAM, Infra, Services teams to gather/share critical information.
- Proactively monitor large/complex migrations and performs health checks to ensure risk is being mitigated where necessary.

Azure Data Engineer, December 2021–October 2022

- Worked in an International Data Migration project; Experience in Azure Data Factory on creating and deploying workflows.
- Monitoring azure pipelines and flagging any data failures. Organizing and analysing data and marketing results
- Responsible for creating and deploying new pipelines, involved in testing the pipelines for the quality of the flow. Also creating new data flow, monitoring existing data flows.
- Provide 24/7 support overnight data processing to prevent impact to business.

Hadoop Job Monitoring Support, December 2021-March 2022

- Worked as a Support Analyst for International Data Lake project; ensuring that all operations of Project Management Process are achieved.
- Responsibilities include detecting, categorizing, prioritizing, and resolving incidents, along with providing necessary support.
- Provided 24/7 support overnight batch processes to prevent impact to business. Additionally, promptly flagged batch failure to the L3 team to avoid Major Issues.

Tata Consultancy Services (SEPTEMBER 2018 – DECEMBER 2021)

Azure Data Engineer, June 2021–December 2021

- Worked as a Support Analyst for an UK based client; Experienced in Azure Data Factory on creating pipelines and workflows to orchestrate data.
- Collaborated on ETL (extract, transform, and load) tasks, maintained data integrity and verified pipeline stability, communicated new or updated data requirement to global team.
- Created blob storage to save raw data sent from streaming analytics.
- Provided 24/7 support overnight data processing to prevent impact to business.

Application Support Analyst/Production Support Analyst, September 2018 - December 2021

- Extensive experience in managing project operations and incident management, including detection, logging, prioritization, and resolution.
- Technical skills include UNIX scripting for issue investigation and SQL query execution for reporting and client needs.
- Supported Blue Yonder applications and provided 24/7 support for critical batch processes.
- The role involved client interaction for requirement gathering, planning major incident procedures, and conducting disaster recovery testing.
- Utilized Dynatrace for application monitoring
- Led a team of 8 members, demonstrating strong leadership and technical proficiency.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Technical support
- SLA/TAT Management
- Client Relationship Management
- Application Troubleshooting & Enhancement

Excellent Communicator, Innovator, collaborator

EDUCATION

BACEHLOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (BCA) DGPA: 7.43

THE HERITAGE ACADEMY, KOLKATA

2018

HIGHER SECONDARY PERCENTAGE: 66.7%

BALLYGUNGE GOVT. HIGH SCHOOL, KOLKATA

2015

SECONDARY PERCENTAGE: 80.7%

RAMKRISHNA MISSION SARADA VIDYAPITH, JAYRAMBATI

2013

ACCOMPLISHMENT

- Best Team award'19 (TCS).
- · Leading team of 8 members.
- Employee of the month July '23
- Best Team Award'24 (Allianz Technology)